hey everybody welcome to this b1 English
listening practice video you can use
this video to practice your listening
and comprehension as I speak you ready
so today I'm gonna talk about
restaurants this is a topic that I could
talk about all day because I love eating
out so let's talk specifically about
American restaurants we could probably
classify American restaurants into
several different categories there are
fast-food restaurants like your typical
burger joints like McDonald's Burger
King jack-in-the-box etc these would
obviously be considered the lowest class
restaurants then there are normal
average restaurants that are chains or
franchises these places usually have
locations all over the country as well
as multiple locations in the same city
then you've got your normal average
restaurants that are individually or
family-owned in the US we sometimes call
family-owned businesses ma and pas
businesses so some of the restaurants in
this category could be called Mon paw
restaurants then you've got your
high-end restaurants which would be
considered fine dining these can be
really fancy and expensive and if
they're really highly acclaimed they
might even have a Michelin star too
needless to say most people can't afford
to eat at these restaurants too often
one of the type of restaurant that's
distinctly American is called a diner
diners are restaurants that sell typical
American food like American breakfast
food burgers sandwiches steak etc a lot
of diners sell breakfast all day so you
can order eggs sausage and pancakes at
9:00 p.m. if you want
I've always loved diners because they
have a really American feel to them
whenever I go on a road trip I always
look forward to stopping in the middle
of nowhere and one of these classic
American diners you can always find
diners off the highway in the middle of
nowhere
all right now let's talk about tipping
in the US this is something that all
foreigners need to know because it's a
custom that's different in the u.s. than
it is in other countries when you eat it
a sit-down restaurant in the US you're
expected to give a tip for the service
you receive there are no exceptions here
even though it's not mandated by law
it's an unspoken rule that all Americans
abide by you have to tip your waiter
whether you feel like it or not so now
you might be wondering how
you have to tip well until recently 15%
has been the standard tip at most
restaurants but in the last few years
they've been trying to raise this
nowadays many restaurants expect 18% or
more which i think is ludicrous I always
give 15% no matter what and this is
still acceptable but there's definitely
a visible effort on the part of
restaurants to raise this percentage so
be aware of this if you're traveling to
the US any time soon lastly let's talk
about the common expressions we use in
the restaurant environment when you
first enter the restaurant and talk to
the host you normally say how many
people there are in your party so you
can say can we have a table for two
please and to order food you can say a
few different things you could say I'll
have the cheeseburger I'll take the
cheeseburger or can I have the
cheeseburger you can use any of these
phrases and just substitute the word
cheeseburger for whatever dish you're
ordering if you want to ask the waiter
for something else after you've already
ordered you can just use the phrase
could I have so for example you could
say could I have another glass of water
please and one more note in the u.s. you
don't ask for the check when you're done
eating the waiter brings it to you
without you asking I know this might
seem weird but it's the custom okay
that's all for today leave a comment and
tell me what your favorite type of
restaurant is I'll see you next time
[Music]
[Applause]